{
    "id": "2cbbba3bd6254213b4d4b1cce9e6cfc5",
    "title": "Conditional Clauses Exercise",
    "questions": [
        {
            "question": "If I were you, I ............................... him right away.",
            "description": "In the second conditional, we use a simple past tense in the if-clause and would + infinitive in the main clause.",
            "answers": [
                "will dismiss",
                "would dismiss",
                "would have dismissed"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "4f746dd72e8c41d680e9354e6ad9a4d5"
        },
        {
            "question": "If I ...................... you, I wouldn't do this.",
            "description": "Was is possible here but were is preferred. ",
            "answers": [
                "am",
                "was",
                "were",
                "Either was or were"
            ],
            "correct": 3,
            "id": "b61efef625144a5195b76314087f6d77"
        },
        {
            "question": "If I had known, I ...................................",
            "description": "In the third conditional, we use a past perfect tense in the if-clause and would have + past participle in the main clause.",
            "answers": [
                "will help",
                "would help",
                "would have helped"
            ],
            "correct": 2,
            "id": "9dcfa3567c22425494e5278565b3f372"
        },
        {
            "question": "Millions of people will die if they ........................ aid soon.",
            "description": "In the first conditional, we use a simple present tense in the if-clause and will + infinitive in the main clause.",
            "answers": [
                "don't receive",
                "won't receive",
                "wouldn't receive"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "0c7067a5c2614054a9236c85f44923e7"
        },
        {
            "question": "........................ you to lose your job, how would you feel?",
            "description": "In the second conditional, we use a simple past tense in the if-clause and would + infinitive in the main clause.",
            "answers": [
                "Were",
                "Had",
                "Will",
                "Should"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "003e0c7c0d0b48c29775e00ee2c2aea9"
        },
        {
            "question": "If I had been there, I ................................. have helped.",
            "description": "In the second conditional, we can use could or might instead of would. ",
            "answers": [
                "would",
                "could",
                "Either could be used here."
            ],
            "correct": 2,
            "id": "53a4663dc9f34a2488924b59e80f913f"
        },
        {
            "question": "If he ....................... in time, he would get the job.",
            "description": "In the second conditional, we use a simple past tense in the if-clause and would + infinitive in the main clause.",
            "answers": [
                "apply",
                "applied",
                "had applied"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "3b90b9692cfe4534ad4ed771be2ee7ed"
        },
        {
            "question": "If the boss ........................ now, we will be in trouble.",
            "description": "In the first conditional, we use a simple present tense in the if-clause and will + infinitive in the main clause.",
            "answers": [
                "arrives",
                "arrived",
                "had arrived"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "df6f958811664b3d8f3fbd77dc0e7dcd"
        },
        {
            "question": "If I liked it, I ......................... it.",
            "description": "In the second conditional, we use a simple past tense in the if-clause and would + infinitive in the main clause.",
            "answers": [
                "will buy",
                "would buy",
                "would have bought"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "ab4c528d5c914b89a0d349e86caf8c94"
        },
        {
            "question": "If she is late, we ....................... without her.",
            "description": "In the first conditional, we use a simple present tense in the if-clause and will + infinitive in the main clause.",
            "answers": [
                "will leave",
                "would leave",
                "would have left"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "bf70bd710a2f49a99d4c92536a1db625"
        },
        {
            "question": "Should you see her, ..............................her to get in touch with me?",
            "description": "Should is often used in the first conditional to suggest that something is unlikely. ",
            "answers": [
                "will you ask",
                "would you ask",
                "would you have asked"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "d431fc0ccf5a474da32fa59f7e30d4df"
        },
        {
            "question": "If he should be late, we ............................. to start without him.",
            "description": "We often suggest that something is unlikely by using should in the if-clause.",
            "answers": [
                "will have to",
                "would have to",
                "Either could be used here"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "1b5581f49be240ffa85f735b1c24af0c"
        }
    ]
}